[It's 1936.]
民国二十五年
[In]
丙子
[cool weather,]
天气渐凉
[there are lush trees]
梧桐苍苍
[and chattering birds.]
燕声成韵
[Nanjing now]
此刻的南京城
[is enjoying its best season.]
是一年中最好的时节
[Various snacks]
凤尾虾
[are everywhere.]
豌豆糕
[Despite the turmoil]
即使八方风雨
[and wars outside,]
时局动荡
[life in Nanjing]
首都城内的时间
[remains peaceful and quiet.]
依然走得不紧不慢
[2 years ago,]
两年前
[I didn't become an official]
我未如父亲心愿
[as my father hoped,]
入仕参政
[but instead joined the army]
而是去往江阴
[in Jiangyin.]
从戎报国
[I'm Hua Zhen.]
我叫华桢
[Now in Phase II of Aeronautical Science]
就读于江阴电雷学校
[at the School of Mining Command.]
航海科二期
[A month later,]
一个月后
[I'll board the ship]
我就将入列登舰
[and study abroad.]
赴远洋学习
[I used to]
往年休假
[study at school during vacations.]
我通常留校用功
[But this year meets my dad's 50th birthday.]
恰逢父亲半百之寿
[My brother told me to be home]
长兄便令我今日三时
[by 15:00 today.]
务必到家
[So many dignitaries]
政商名流
[and celebrities]
达官显宦
[gathering here happily,]
无不齐聚欢喜
[unaware of the world outside]
殊不知一墙内外
[in dire straits.]
已是两个世界
[It's been over 2 years since I last came back.]
上次回来已是两年多前
[Everything is both familiar]
眼前的一切既熟悉
[and strange.]
又有些陌生
Young Master.
少爷
Mom.
妈
Zhen.
桢儿
I'm waiting for you.
一直在等你呢
How's the ride?
怎么样
Are you tired?
路上累吗
No.
不累
Have you seen your father?
见过你爸爸了吗
Not yet.
还没有
He may be talking
他可能跟你哥哥
with your brother in the study.
在书房谈事儿呢
Let's go to see him.
咱们去跟他打个招呼吧
Fine.
好
[Zhen is home!]
桢儿回来了
Zhen.
到了
Liang.
哥
How about your ride?
怎么样 路上顺利吗
I asked the driver
我特意让司机
to meet you at the dock early.
提前去码头等你
I saw him as soon as I got off.
一下船就看见他了
Father.
爸
Have you greeted the guests?
跟客人打过招呼了吗
Not yet.
还没有
Next time,
遇到这种情况
greet the guests first.
要先跟客人打招呼
It's basic etiquette.
这是基本的礼仪
You take him later.
一会儿你带他去
Got it.
好
[I'm gonna go]
我去看一下
check on the lunch preparations.
午宴准备怎么样了
Take your time.
你们慢慢聊
Time flies.
时间过得真快啊
It should
你从
have been 2 years since you
陆军大学转到电雷学校
transferred to the S.M.C.
已经两年了吧
Just now we're
刚才我和爸爸
talking about your school.
还聊到电雷学校
The new Navy
说以后新海军
will depend on you
就靠你们这些
young students.
年轻的学生了
[He's a second lieutenant now.]
他现在是个少尉
After graduation,
毕了业
he can only be a lieutenant.
不过是个中尉而已
A long way to go.
路要慢慢走
How long will you stay this time?
这次准备在南京待多久
[A month at most.]
最多一个月
[A month?]
一个月
[And after that?]
那往后呢
[Go back to that school?]
继续待在那个电雷学校
You'll graduate in 2 years, right?
再过两年就毕业了吧
After that,
毕业之后
do you wanna work with father
要不要去军政部
in the Ministry of Military Affairs?
跟着爸爸
I'm not planning that at present.
目前还没这个打算
I still want
我的兴趣
to join the Navy.
还是在海军
[Don't you know?]
你知道吗
[The Navy Dept. keeps]
海军部到现在
[going to the Ministry of Military Affairs]
还三天两头地
to protest from time to time,
跑到军政部抗议
saying that your school
说你们电雷学校
is on its own party.
是军中有军
I've heard it at school.
我在学校听人提过
Stop talking it at home.
不要在家讨论这些事情
Let's go.
走吧
Minister He is coming.
何部长应该快到了
Since you're determined
既然你执意
to stay at the S.M.C.,
留在电雷学校
[I hope you can shoulder]
我也希望你能
[your responsibility.]
堪重任
Take it easy at home.
都到家了 放松点儿
Thank you for coming.
各位 那先失陪了
Enjoy yourself.
请随意
Thanks.
好
How dare you fight back?
还敢还手
This is my present
这是我给爸爸
for father.
买的生日礼物
C'mon,
给我干什么
give him yourself.
自己给爸爸去
You do it.
你帮我交给他
You're always relaxed in front of me.
跟我就敢没大没小
But why so embarrassed
给爸爸送个生日礼物
to give him a birthday present?
需要这么不好意思吗
I'm not used to doing this.
我不习惯给他送东西
You should at least
那你至少出去
greet the guests outside.
跟人家认识认识
At father's birthday party,
今天爸爸五十大寿
you're eating here
你自己一个人
all by yourself.
在这儿吃饭
You think it's fine?
算什么呢
I don't know them.
我又不认识那些人
What should I say?
也不知道跟他们说什么
And you
再说了
the first secretary,
不是还有你这个
will do it perfectly.
侍从室第一秘书在吗
Anything to do with me?
跟我有什么关系
You're my brother.
你是我哥
Won't you help me?
你不管我
You've been using me as a shield
你从小到大就知道
your whole life.
拿我当挡箭牌
By the way,
对了
I learned from mom
听妈妈说
that you're enrolled into the elite class.
你被选入精英班了
Let's have a drink
必须得喝一杯
to celebrate it.
庆祝一下
[Step aside, please!]
来 让让 让让
[Don't look back.]
别回头
[A car from the Shanghai Garrison Command.]
淞沪警备司令部的车
They're chasing us from Shanghai to Nanjing.
他们从上海追到南京了
Turn inside.
拐进去
Out of the way!
让让 让让
Mr. Deng,
邓先生
just put the book
您就按原计划
under the cushion as planned.
把书放在坐垫底下
I'll take it away
您一下车
after you go.
我就把书带走
Then you'll be the target,
我下车他们会查你
getting the book in danger.
书肯定保不住
Get on the car.
上车
[We need]
我们需要
[to find a way to get the book out]
在他们发现这本书之前
[before it was found.]
想办法把书转移出去
Way out!
让让
Is Yihe road near here?
颐和路是不是在附近
Just a turn ahead.
前面转个弯就是
Take me to No. 23 Yihe road.
送我去颐和路二十三号
[Can you get out?]
您能脱身吗
At any rate,
不管能不能脱身
the book must be sent to Shanghai.
这本书必须要送到上海
Captain,
队长
they're heading for Yihe road.
后边就是颐和路
Shall we act now?
现在动手吗
No rush.
不急
Follow him
跟上他
and take a look.
走走看
The Chairman said
委员长说
the S.M.C. is the cradle of the revolutionary navy.
电雷学校是革命新海军
If war ever comes,
如果有一天上战场
the elite class
我们精英班
will be the vanguard of the new navy.
就是新海军的先锋
[Do you really think]
你真觉得
the government will fight with Japan?
政府会和日本人打起来
Last year,
去年
the Communist Party
共产党登在
issued the August First Declaration
《救国报》上的
at the National Salvation Newspaper.
《八一宣言》
We read it at school.
我们在学校都看到了
[The Chinese nation]
中华民族
[is at a critical point]
已经处在
[of survival.]
生死存亡的关头
Resisting Japanese aggression
抗日救国是全体中国人
is the top task facing all Chinese.
面临的首要任务
At least that's true.
至少这句话说得没错
As father said,
还是爸爸那句话
you can stay out of politics,
政治你可以不插手
but you can't be insensitive
但是你不能不敏感
or cautious.
不谨慎
Since Minister He
何部长上任军政部部长
took office,
这几年来
internal disputes have been constant.
内部纷争一直不断
[You are the son of the deputy minister.]
你是军政部次长的儿子
[Don't say]
这些话
these again
以后就算在家里
even at home.
也不要说了
Liang,
哥
resisting aggression is not politics.
抗日不是政治
The chaos in Guangdong and Guangxi
两广生变
was in such a name.
打的可就是抗日的旗号
Then what?
结果怎么样
Cantonese Military fell apart.
粤军四分五裂
Chen Jitang immediately
陈济棠眼看大事不妙
stole into Hong Kong.
私渡到香港
[Isn't this politics?]
你觉得这不是政治
[What is that?]
这是什么
Thanks.
谢谢
Sir.
你好 先生
Your invitation please.
请出示下请柬
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I was in such a hurry
我出门太着急了
that I forgot
忘记带了
it.
请柬
This is my identity card.
这是我的证件
I'm a former subordinate of the deputy minister.
我是华次长的老部下
Captain.
队长
This is the home of the deputy minister He.
他进了军政部华次长家
So what?
那又怎么了
It's no use asking anyone for help.
找谁求救都没有用
Let's
走
go get him out.
我们去把他请出来
Excuse me,
你好
your invitation please.
请出示下请柬
We come from
我们是
the Shanghai Garrison Command.
淞沪警备司令部的人
We're on a mission.
从上海过来执行公务
What happened?
怎么了
Captain.
队长
They're from
他们是
the Shanghai Garrison Command.
淞沪警备司令部的人
We've been
我们一直在调查
tracking a man.
追踪的一个人
He's allowed in just now.
被这兄弟给放进去了
We wanna go in to find him
我也想进去找那个人
for some words.
询问几句
Could you do us a favor?
不知道方便不方便
Today is deputy minister's birthday.
今天是华次长的寿宴
I'm sorry I can't help you.
恐怕不太方便
We are
我们也是过来
on a public mission.
执行公务的
For this reason,
在上海抓人
no one ever stopped us
还没有遇到过
when we're in Shanghai.
不让进门的
Here is the capital
这里是首都
Nanjing,
南京
not Shanghai.
不是上海
Sorry for that.
抱歉了
[Mr. Deng.]
邓老师
C'mon mate,
这位兄弟
we are all soldiers,
我们都是军人
and both on our mission.
大家都在执行公务
Understanding is appreciated.
能不能理解一下
Imagine
万一
what would happen if something wrong
被放进去的那个人
with the man.
真的有问题
We may make trouble for Mr. He.
咱不是给次长添麻烦吗
How about this?
你看这样行不行
I'll go in alone
就我一个人进去
and won't cause you any trouble.
绝不给次长添麻烦
Just 10 minutes.
就十分钟
I'm from Phase II
军政部电雷学校二期
of Aeronautical Science
航海科三班学员
at the S.M.C.
华桢
I'm Hua Zhen!
向您报到
Long time no see!
好久不见
I didn't expect
没想到来参加
to see you here
你父亲的生日宴
at your dad's birthday party.
在这儿能遇到你
I'm on vacation.
学校刚好放假
And I just arrived in Nanjing today.
我也是今天刚到的南京
Mr. Deng,
老师
let me take you to my father.
我带您去见父亲
Wait.
等一下
going out in a hurry
出门太匆忙
I was all sweaty.
走了一身汗
It's an indecent way
这样去见你父亲
to meet your father.
实在有些不雅
Would you mind taking me to tidy up?
方便带我去整理一下吗
Once inside,
进去之后
act cautiously.
记得谨言慎行
Do you remember?
您还记得吗
In 1924, the former premier
民国十三年在广州
[boarded in Guangzhou and sailed north]
先总理登永丰舰北上
[You're the second officer.]
您是二副
I was 12 at that time
那年我十二岁
and attended the ceremony with my father.
随父亲参加了送行仪式
Luckily, I was on board with you,
有幸随您登舰
feeling the great ship
一睹轮船之奇
and the vast ocean.
沧海之阔
Hua Zhen.
华桢
Oh,
对了
I still have the books
您送我的那些书
you gave me.
学生都还留着
About
关于
First Sino-Japanese War,
甲午海战的
Russo-Japanese War.
日俄战争的
And your favorite collection of essays.
还有您钟爱的文集
Worry about the world
身无半亩
even if penniless.
心忧天下
Learn from the ancients
读破千卷
by reading books.
神交古人
The knowledge you've taught me
您教我的这些知识
has helped me
学生
gain a lot.
受益匪浅
All I can do is building ships
我现在离开海军
after out of the navy.
只会造船
I'm no longer
实在是不敢称为
your teacher.
你的老师
But it was you
您虽然离开了海军
who pushed me
但我立志加入海军
to join the navy
穷天地 保家国
to serve the country.
确实是受到了您的影响
You're my first teacher
您是我在海军的
in the navy.
第一位老师
Hua Zhen.
华桢
Could you do me a favor?
我有事相托
[The moment of human choice.]
人类的选择时刻
Please
我想拜托你
bring this book
帮我把这本书
to a friend of mine in Shanghai.
送给我上海的一位朋友
Is it a hurry?
要得很急吗
Must be delivered at 2:00 p.m.
后天下午两点
the day after tomorrow.
务必送到
Excuse me.
借过
Sorry to bother.
不好意思
Have you seen a man
向您问个客人
in a black gown.
大概穿个黑色长衫
About this high.
这么高
Is it important to you?
这件事对您很重要吗
Extremely.
至关重要
Got it.
好
I'll buy a train ticket right away.
我马上去买火车票
Remember,
记住
the address is Room 311
地址在复兴东路
of Van Hwa Hotel
文华饭店
on Fuxing East Road.
三一一房间
Find Mr. Meng
男主人姓孟
and give to him yourself.
一定要亲手交给他
And the reason...
具体原因
It's fine.
没事儿
I…
我
You don't have to tell me
您如果不方便说
about it.
可以不用告诉我
Don't let anyone
千万不能让任何人
know about it.
知道这件事
Trust me.
学生记住了
Repeat the address.
重复地址
There.
在那边呢
He's talking with the young master.
跟我们二少爷在书房
That room?
那个房间
Yes.
对
Thank you.
谢谢
You're welcome.
不客气
Looking forward to seeing you
等你从上海回来
back from Shanghai.
我们再见
Sir.
老师
I have a question
学生一直有个问题
for you.
想要问您
What's it?
你说
I know you left the navy 'cause you're sick
我知道您当初离开海军
of ceaseless factional disputes
是因为厌恶了派系之间
and the politicians with
无休无止的斗争
their own intentions.
政治是各为其主
But I never tie the resistance against
但学生始终认为
Japanese aggression to politics.
抗日不是政治
The northeast China has fallen.
东北沦陷
The north China is endangered.
华北事变
We will finally be at war
我们终有一天
with those Japanese invaders.
会和日寇一战
If we have to fight one day,
如果真的到了那一天
will you return to the battlefield?
您会重回战场吗
Sure.
会
I will.
一定会
Hello, Chief Deng.
邓室长
My name is Wei Daiqing
我叫魏岱擎
and I'm here to pick you up.
是特地来接您的
Thanks,
小兄弟
mate.
辛苦了
What do you mean?
什么意思
Get on.
上车吧
Chief Deng.
邓室长
[In Nanjing,]
在南京
[you're the chief of New Warship]
你是海军部造船所
[Supervising Office of the Navy Shipyard.]
新舰监造室的室长
In Shanghai,
在上海
you work for Undercover Work Group
你是中共地下小组的
of the Communist Party.
组长
Am I right?
我没说错吧
Chief Deng.
邓组长
Your Party organization
你们共产党的组织
in Shanghai
在上海
has been beaten by us.
已经被我们打没了
Even the Central Committee
连你们的党中央
has fled
都被我们追得
to the northwest in panic.
满西北乱窜
But you're still holding up.
你还在坚持
Rather than
对你
respect you,
我谈不上钦佩
but I have some sympathy
但一点点同情心
for you.
还是有的
Tell me.
说说吧
Who else are your comrades
你还有哪些同党
hiding in Shanghai
跟你一样
and fighting
躲在上海
for each other.
各自为战
I will appeal to the navy.
我会向海军部提出申诉
After a tree is pulled out,
树都拔了
it's normal to see residual roots
土里总会留下一些
left in the earth.
残根
But it's OK.
没关系
They will be cleaned up.
会刨干净的
Please show me your ticket.
先生麻烦看下票
Here.
给
Thank you.
可以了先生
Your ticket, please.
麻烦您 看下票
Thanks.
谢谢
["How fortunate it is]
青春年少时
[to have achieved]
得显己志
[one's aspirations at a young age."]
乃人生之大幸也
[It's a quote which Mr. Deng]
这是邓铭远先生
[wrote on the title page.]
于扉页的亲笔
[Shanghai]
上海
[is a dazzling pearl in the Far East]
远东的一颗明珠
[as well as a paradise for risk takers.]
同时也是冒险家的乐园
[On the old and moist stone streets,]
古老潮湿的石板街道上
[dreams]
梦想
[rise up with avarice.]
往往与贪婪齐飞
[Ambitions]
野心
[grow stronger with violence.]
时常共暴力一色
[Under its unique grace and charm]
优雅风情的涟漪之下
[hide the complexity of life]
人生百态
[and the turbulence of revolution.]
暗流涌动
[To help Mr. Deng present the book to a friend,]
为邓先生送书赠友人
[I]
我
[came to Shanghai.]
来到了这里
[Sugar-coated figurine!]
糖人
Excuse me.
阿姨
I want one.
我想要一个糖人
Sure.
好
Which one do you want?
你要哪一个
This one!
这个
OK.
好
Thank you.
谢谢你 给你钱
Goodbye!
再见
You're welcome.
不客气
Look up there.
老婆 你看他们
They're out of the window again.
又爬出来了
So dangerous!
那是在干吗 多危险
[They are professional.]
他们专业的
[Have you ever met before?]
先生没见过吧
There're always
那面墙上
some people climbing on that wall
经常有人爬来爬去的
like spiders.
个个赛蜘蛛
[We're]
我们
[inured to the unusual.]
都见怪不怪了
Enjoy yourself.
您慢用
[2 p.m. the day after tomorrow.]
后天下午两点
[Room 311 of Van Hwa Hotel]
复兴东路 文华饭店
[on Fuxing East Road.]
三一一房间
[Find Mr. Meng]
男主人姓孟
[and give the book to him yourself.]
一定要亲手交给他
Sorry.
对不起
Look at you.
买什么玩具
You just wanna buy toys every day.
天天就知道买玩具
Police. Anybody inside?
警察 有人吗
Hello.
你好
Have you ever met
有看见一个
someone wearing overalls?
穿背带裤的人吗
[Overalls?]
背带裤
[No.]
没有
[I've been in my room.]
我一直在屋里呢
[Thank you.]
好 谢谢
[Sir,]
警官 您好
[are you looking for someone?]
您找人吗
[Have you met]
看见一个
[a man in overalls?]
穿背带裤的人吗
[No.]
没有
[Thanks.]
好 谢谢
Do you live in Room 311?
你住在三一一
What happened?
屋里发生了什么事情
I think he's gone.
那个人应该走了
It's bloody all over.
屋里到处都是血
[Dad,]
爸爸
[mum,]
妈妈
[and dad's friends]
还有爸爸的朋友
[are all lying on the floor.]
他们都躺在地上
They're
我
still alive when I went to
我出去买糖人的时候
buy the sugar-coated figurine.
他们还都好好的
A police officer at the door.
门口有警察
I can help you report the case.
我可以帮你报警
That bad guy is a cop too.
那个坏人他也是警察
He has a gun
他有枪
and wears a police cap and uniform.
戴了警帽 还穿了警服
[Just stay in the room.]
待在屋子里别动
Please
求求你
don't leave me alone.
别把我一个人扔在这里
[I'm afraid the police outside]
外面那个警察
is a bad guy too.
万一也是坏人怎么办
My dad's surname is Meng.
我爸爸姓孟
Are you his friend?
你是他的朋友对吗
No.
不
I don't know him.
我不认识你们
Please
求求你
take me with you.
带我一起走吧
Remember,
记住
don't leave.
待在屋子里
Sir,
警官
what has happened
里面到底
in the room?
发生什么事儿了
You should
问过你
leave the place quickly.
赶紧离开这个地方
Hurry up.
快点
Which room do you live in?
你住哪个房间
302.
三零二
Hey you, stop!
穿西装那个 等一下
Stay there.
等一下
I'm the police.
警察
Do you live in this hotel?
你是这儿的房客吗
No.
不
I'm here to visit my friend.
我是来拜访朋友
Have you heard
刚才听见周围
something strange around?
有什么异常的动静吗
No.
没有
Have you met
有看见什么
someone weird moving about?
奇怪的人走动吗
No.
没有
Or have you seen a child
那有没有看见
holding a sugar-coated figurine?
一个拿糖人的小孩儿
Sorry,
抱歉
no.
真没有
Do you live nearby?
你住这附近吗
Tell me your address
留个地址
and we need you for a statement.
回头需要你做个笔录
Sorry.
不好意思
I'm here to travel
我是来旅游的
and will leave tomorrow.
明天就走
I'm afraid I can't help you.
恐怕帮不了你
Why do you bring an English book when traveling?
出来旅行带本英文书
It's German.
这是德文
Sir,
警官
can I leave now?
我可以走了吗
The security in the vicinity is not good.
附近治安不太好
Don't wander about.
别到处乱走 注意安全
Don't go in there!
别进去
Get out!
出来 出来
What happened here?
这发生什么事儿了这
Which room does your friend live in?
你朋友住哪个屋
Show me
来
your check-in registration.
住房登记给我看一下
OK.
在这儿 在这儿
Turn to that page.
来 翻给我看
Who did this?
这谁干的
It's me.
是我
A temporary warning line.
临时拉的警戒线
Your certificate.
证件
Fule Station House?
福乐警察所
I'm Chen Hao,
十六铺分局下属
the capital of the Fourth Station House
第四警察所
under the Shiliupu Police Station.
队长陈浩
[The 3 deceased]
三名死者
[were given throat cuts with sharp tools.]
都是被利器割喉
[Only a young man]
房间住客
[registered for the resident.]
只登记了一名年轻男性
[Based on bed allocation,]
根据床铺情况
[the other two]
来判断的话
[are couples.]
另外一男一女是对夫妻
There are also
房间里面
some clothes for a child.
还有一些小孩儿衣物
A kid is supposed to live here.
应该住了一名小孩儿
Tenants around
周围房客
didn't hear anything strange.
没有听见异常动静
[No witness for now.]
暂时没有找到目击者
Anything else?
没了
I found this in the front
这是我在房间门口
of the door.
捡到的
Basically,
买糖人的
children would buy such stuff.
大多数都是小孩儿
It may fall
很有可能是
out of the girl who lived in the room.
房间里面女孩儿掉的
If she was in the room,
如果她当时在屋内的话
she might have been abducted
很有可能是被劫持
or have escaped already.
或者逃走
I have checked
我刚检查了
the clothes.
女孩儿的衣物
For a girl around 6 or 7 years old.
差不多六七岁吧
Good job.
好
Have you caught the suspect
你上个案子追的嫌疑人
in the previous case?
抓到了吗
Not yet.
还没有
Take it.
拿着
Do your own job.
忙你的事儿去吧
We will take over this case.
这儿不用你管了
Captain's out.
这不队长吗
Cap.
队长
[Do your own job.]
忙你的事儿去吧
[We will take over this case.]
这儿不用你管了
Cap.
队长
The overalls have gone.
背带裤跑了
We didn't catch up.
我们没追上
Then keep doing.
跑了就继续追
Here comes a new case.
另外又有新案子了
Another one?
怎么又来新案子了
Can you
不是
persuade the leader
你跟所长申请一下
to assign it to other houses?
派给别的所呗
You've crouched the overalls
你在舞厅蹲了两天
at the ballroom for two days.
才蹲着背带裤
Don't you feel tired?
你不累啊
You need a bath!
你都臭了
The overalls
队长
fled to a restaurant
背带裤为了躲我们
in order to hide from us.
跑到饭店里去了
We're all exhausted
我们这楼上楼下的
for endless manhunt.
腿都快跑断了
Alright, then take a break,
那就休息一下
have a bath,
回去洗个澡
take more spare sets of clothes,
顺便多带两身衣服
and prepare to live in the office.
最近做好不回家的准备
What? Again?
队长 又不能回家了
Fine.
行了
Stop complaining
甭抱怨了
[Newspaper!]
卖报
[Sir, do you need a newspaper?]
先生 买报吗
I need a phone call.
我打电话
Stay outside.
在外面等我
Hello,
喂 你好
I want to transfer a toll.
我想挂个长途
Nanjing.
南京
New Warship Supervising Office
海军部造船所
of the Navy Shipyard.
新舰监造室
[Has he mentioned or met]
他有提起过什么人吗
[someone?]
跟什么人见过
[Sorry,]
没什么接触
[I don't know.]
这个不太了解
[Then has he been]
那他这一个月
[in the past month?]
都去过哪些地方
[Hello.]
喂 你好
[I wanna speak to]
我想找邓铭远
[Deng Mingyuan.]
邓室长
He's not here.
邓室长他不在
May I ask where he is?
请问他去哪儿了
[He went on a business trip]
邓室长有公务在身
[to another city.]
去外地了
May I ask
请问
for your name?
您是哪位
[Do you like it?]
喜欢吗
[Yeah!]
喜欢
[It's for you.]
好 你拿着
Which one do you like?
来 喜欢哪个
I want this.
妈妈我要这个
OK.
好嘞
How about this one?
这个吧
Are you from other places to Shanghai?
你们是从外地来上海的
No.
不是
We live here.
我们就是上海的
Then why do you live in the hotel?
那为什么要住在饭店里
Dad said our house was in water leakage.
爸爸说家里的房子漏水
We're about
不能住了
to move to Guangzhou.
得搬去广州住一段时间
We just lived in the hotel for some days.
这几天暂时住在饭店
We'll leave
等有人把船票
as long as we receive the boat tickets
和新的证件送过来了
and new credentials.
我们就走
Is your name Li Qiushi?
你叫黎秋实
No, I'm
我姓孟
Meng Duoci.
孟多慈
Why it is Li Qiushi
那为什么这个证件上
on the credential?
写的黎秋实
Dad said
爸爸说
we need to use a new name
等我们去广州以后
after reaching Guangzhou.
都要改用新的名字
But
不过
he didn't tell me why.
他没有告诉我为什么
Are they your parents?
这是你的父母
What about him called Xiang Yuansheng?
那这个叫向远生的人呢
He's dad's friend
他是爸爸的朋友
and this name is fake too.
这个名字也是假的
Big brother.
哥哥
You're here
你就是那个
to bring us tickets
给我们送船票
and new credentials.
和新证件的人
[Please]
我想拜托你
[bring this book]
帮我把这本书
[to a friend of mine in Shanghai.]
送给我上海的一位朋友
No.
不是
[I'm requested by someone]
我是受人之托
[to give you the novel.]
来给你们送小说的
[Now you've got the book.]
现在东西也送到了
[And I 've paid for the meal.]
饭钱我已经付过了
You're local.
你既然是本地人
So you must
那在这儿
have someone else that you know here.
应该还有认识的人吧
[You can contact them]
一会儿联系看看
to take care of you.
谁能照顾你
I'll send you there.
我把你送过去
Where are you going?
那你去哪儿呢
Go home.
回家